So I guess you guys have also maybe
there's also a lot of very good good
class previously just like by by young
by gentile
yeah by a lot of other people in the
class. So I'm think when I'm I asked to
talk about this I'm think about okay
what I should talk about. So, so this is
why I choose to talk about okay. So,
probably I should talk about something
maybe that's not share in the textbook
but I think actually is the what is
really working in our daily work when we
are training this kind the last scale of
the models. So my name is Wu Chan. So
here's about me. So I'm a I'm an
engineer. I'm a also a researcher as
well. So basically I lead the geni team
and the coi the pch training teams. So
poor training for today most of the
effort is in the reinforce learning
Chinese. So I get my PhD in the Hong
Kong US and I work in the MSR and come
to US in the 20 2012. So basically I've
been in Microsoft for about 20 years and
split between the MSR and the product
team but now actually I'm in the product
team and also because I'm more
passionate about how can we build a
product that's really working and it's
also interesting actually I found when I
am in the product team actually even my
research actually is much more
productive when you are in the product
team today. So I as you can see most of
the work here actually was done was done
when I was in the product team. So yeah
so I yeah I think that's about me and
the next step I think I would love to
talk about for example just like use
this as example. So how can we build up
this kind the agentic model? So my
effort here today is more like about the
model training instead of the model
inference because I I still truly
believe actually if you want to improve
the model quality you need this kind of
the end to end chaining to make things
happen to build the best models. So here
just about an example of the coding
agents. It doesn't mean we just working
on the coding. We're also working on
something something else. But I think
coding actually is a really good example
to share how the model was trained today
in the industry. So because a lot of
people here actually use the V code,
GitHub copilot cursor whatever because
and for example just like here is about
one the example just like you go to the
GitHub you have the GitHub issue and you
also have this kind of the codebase and
basically that's your report. So the
issue basically you will describe okay
what they want to solve for example this
is the bug I want to fix this bug
something like that and that's the in
the lab and definitely here you have the
model your model is going to try to
solve this problems but I think besides
there's also a lot of other things yeah
one is about the environment simulator
so because you need to run the code you
need to run the test and this mostly is
didn't run in your local machine and
actually is running in the same box So
you have the very this kind of the very
large scale of the environment
simulator. So yeah environment simulator
most of the m is running on the CPU
today and so basically but the number of
the CPU here definitely it could be at
least 10x of the lumber of the GPU
today. So that's also pretty huge today
and for this kind of the simulator
basically you can do a lot of thing and
the most interesting thing is about the
length model is going to communicate
with the simulator to run so many
different things for multiple times and
this is the multi-turn conversations
basically you can think about this way
and finally the length model we think
about oh yes actually after I do all
these kind of thing I can generate
something now to fix the issue so you're
going to generate a pull request
something like that and this pull
request is going to get back to the
users and the user will do continual
interaction to say oh maybe you didn't
give me the right pull request I need to
change something additionally so it's
this kind the multiple turn conversation
continually so that is about a very
typical agent model changing wrong and
definitely there's a lot of other things
and they're also going to do the unit
test during this kind the when the
environment and language model we ask
can you run test for this And then after
that actually you're going to tell me so
whether the test pass or not.
So basically for example if you want to
say about okay what is about the
agentical trainings definitely there are
so many different things about the agent
training but I think there's a few thing
definitely is very important for example
just like based on the examples one is
about you need to be very goal oriented
you you have a goal you want to achieve
whether it's the mass problem or whether
it is about you want to the model to
generate the pull request for you so
that is the goal that's the is a goal
and this pull request also have a lot of
require requirement just like you need
to solve the problem. you need to be
able to pass all the unit test whatever
and basically I think another thing is
about the two-way usage and this two-way
usage just like in just like I mentioned
is there's a simulator there you have a
simulator and you want to ask this
simulator to run a lot of things so and
this two-way usage actually is multiple
turn it's not a single turn actually the
communication is pretty complicating
sometimes and you also need to the model
also need to do the planning and the
planning mean that actually the model
need to decide okay what I should do
first and second and the model also need
to reasoning because actually the model
is going to decide what I need to do
next based on the current status based
on the current feedback and including
from the model itself or including from
this kind the simulator so you need to
do the reasoning that's why for example
you can see that the reasoning model is
so suitable for this kind of the
identical model training there's some
reason there so because the model really
needed and also in a real system
actually there also need to consider is
the user interaction the the model need
to listen to the user based on the
current context so what is going wrong
what can be improved something like that
and to achieve all this goal there's so
many things but I think for today I'll
only talk about a few things that's
pretty simple because I think maybe this
kind of thing actually is a little bit
different than your understanding from
some other place based on my experience
in the industry so first one is the data
because I think data actually nobody
will underestimate the importance of the
data. So we can also share maybe for
example what we have done on the data
side. So the other one is a greater is
the evaluation. So I think young in the
first in the first class already
mentioned actually reinforce learning
agent model training is more about how
you define the evaluation how you define
the greater but it's not that easy to
define the greater. So and the other one
actually I want to say talk about is
about the efficiency for example because
when you running with this kind of
thousands of GPU the efficiency actually
define a lot of things how whether you
can run it very very stable and the last
part actually I didn't mention here is
going to about I'm going to talk about
also in this kind of the direction what
is the next what is the most interesting
thing here
so for the data so I think everybody
think about know about actually we have
two kinds of data
One is about the data actually the
result can be verified we call as
verifiable so just like math just like
coding you can run the unit test just
like dam actually just like the test
ABCD you also have the have the right
answer I think in my opinion actually
this kind the verifiable definitely
super good so it's actually bringing a
lot of intelligence but in the real
product a lot of thing actually is not
verifiable it's very hard for you to
verify whether this is the ground truth
or not and it's pretty open. For
example, there are so many different
things. There's no verifiable just like
whether we show the code to the user
whether this code is in the good style.
For example, just like although whether
this writing or this representation is
in the good style, whether you like it
or you don't like it is very subjective
I want to say. So the other one is
writing for example you ask the language
model to write a poem for you or
whatever for you different people
different opinion. So this is not very
easy to verify the safety or maybe this
safe for the for him but it's not safe
for the other persons. So I think we
already know about this but I think
there's also one of the thing there are
two thing actually I want to talk about
today. One is called the rubrics. So
that's how things work. Actually in the
in touch lab we build a lot of rubrics
and this is also something pretty
special. Maybe I'm going to show you
example. So it's much more complicated
than most people think. And rubrics
actually we we basically have a lot of
very good people to write this kind of
the rubrics. The other one actually I
want to mention about is the data
synthesis. So the data synthesis is so
important when you're trying to run a
lot of this kind of the product. So
because the data sync is actually is the
most scalable way you are able to
synchize the data and at the beginning
maybe previously we think about okay
maybe building data is just some dirty
work I want to share with you now I put
the best person best in the team to
build up the data how to synize the data
actually is the most important thing to
make the model much better especially
for the model in the product so for the
rubrics so let's say about for example I
think the right side actually is the
examples it's a example for the rule for
the rubrics You can think about this is
the questions and actually the basic
idea is about you this is a this is a
question you can also ask the human
expert to write a ground truth based on
their opinions but I think this is not
enough this is previously but now
actually we want the human to write this
kind of criteria and there's it's no
surprise to me for example for question
there's 50 criterias and each criteria
it need to be super clear and very
detailed and human is able to read and
it's also very structured. It's also
able to score to give a maybe for
example if you respond this thing
actually the score is one or zero or
whatever it's able to be score because
the the scoring actually this define how
the reinforced learning during the
learning actually how to run the grader
and this is going to be the input for
the grader and so basically this kind of
thing is the definitely this is super
useful for example justify for this kind
of open domain questions and open
questions because it's really hard to
measure. So what is the right answer or
no? So if you're not able to measure
this way so the way is to split into
fine finer grain and then for each of
the piece actually we measure okay this
is good or bad and we try to measure
that because if you cannot measure that
you cannot learn that's the most
important thing and the other one
actually I want to say is about
effort to write down each of the example
actually for today is very expensive
sometimes for asper they can spend a few
hours or or a few Okay, just like write
up all these kind of the criteria. It's
pretty normal. So it's not like just
like write the ground truth anymore and
you need to be very comprehensive. For
example, all the criteria I write up
together is able to cover all the aspect
for example for these questions. So
whether it's able to really measure the
answer so because in this case for no
matter which kind of answer you can use
the rubric to measure how good is the
answers. So and the other one is about
quality is more important. So most of
this actually we don't need so many we
ask the language model to do a lot of
generalizations but so quality actually
is much more important than quantity and
for here I just want to ask a question
we say about this expensive quity is
important but how many is need so I
think is so I think a very extreme case
is about how about we just have one
single examples we just write one single
example can we get the model to learn to
a very good qualities
because when you guys do about this kind
of the SAP or even you use this thing to
train a reward model one single example
is not enough right it's always not
enough because it's very hard to say
maybe using one single example but we
did do a work like this
yes
we did do this work is about for the
reinforcement learning with the verify
reward you just use it to chain with one
single example what is going to look
like. So this is for the math work. So
because definitely this is important but
I think when you do the research
actually we use the public benchmark to
verify a lot of things. So you can see
that in the lab this diagram the
interesting thing is about this one
actually the dot line is about based on
the training from 1,200 examples
and for this green line basically it's
just one use one single examples. We
just use one single example to change
the reinforce learning. It's really one
single example. We just
keep working and keep it try to verify
the answer whether it's correct or not
and you can see that actually you can go
up keep going up and finally actually
it's very close to the case actually you
used to chain with 1,000 more than 1,000
examples
this is very very amazing right
because if you just use one single
example it mean that actually when you
do the is really not trying to remember
these examples you try to understand
actually how to solve the math problem
but the evaluation say have so many
different questions so evation set is
the same and that is one example I want
to say but I think the other point I
want to make is about
the variance so how to pick this one
single example is also very important it
doesn't mean that every example is good
enough for you to train using one single
examples
right so how we pick the one single
example here is about basically we try
to calculate the variance
For this example, for example, for this
problem, we use the model to roll out
whether they are very difference or
they're almost the same. So basically we
prefer the difference
there as we are going to about how can
we encourage this kind of the
exploration. We want the model and the
example based on this model actually
have different kinds of the roll out in
the reinforce learning. So because the
more you have actually the better we can
learn we can observe for the model and
we can see that actually based on this.
So there's one example based on this
rating for example this pi one actually
is much better than the pi 17. I just
give you example based on the qualities.
So this definitely tell us a lot of
interesting thing about reinforce
learning.
The RL data actually is very different
than the SFT or the ILF or the DMO
datas. So I think the difference
basically it mean the power of the
exploration is different. Now if we use
this way you have much more power for
the for the exploration you able to
explore much more. So we understand
actually using this example is it's not
just about memorizations. It's not just
about you try to memorize this problem
actually use this problem to understand
what is the building block for math how
to solve the math problem just using one
single examples
and the second one definitely is about
it's extremely high data efficiency
there's a difference for example what
the difference between IO today and
what's the previous work is super high
efficiency if you're able to pick the
right data you have a very good learning
policy so and definitely As I mentioned
about the quality really matter here a
lot. So so that that is one of the big
the first point I want to make.
The second point I want to make actually
definitely in the industry training you
have so many different examples so many
different task. For example, just like
what we say about when you train a code
model, it's not just about the pull
request for the coding model, people
also go there to ask some a lot of L
coding questions also ask a lot of
question uh question answering right for
example okay can you write a document
for me based on the code so there are so
many different kind of datas so in the
industry lab actually I want to say for
the data work it's not only about the
source data itself most of the effort
actually spend on how can you mix the
data For example, this data actually is
3%, data t is 20%. So we just keep
changing a lot of this kind the data
mixing when you change the final model
and so the data actually is super
important when you do the mix and for
example it's also very different. You
also keep changing the data mixing
during the training. For example, at the
beginning we probably we can put in a
little bit more of the easier data to
get the model learn to
this level. The model can learn about
this but when the training move forward
the model become stronger and stronger
actually you are trying to mix in more
and more difficult data. That's also how
a very basic thing we did.
And so you can also try to combine syn
more synthetic data and for example if
you want the data but you need this data
you know your model actually is very
good in this three category but it's not
very good in the other two category. So
how can you solve that? So the way to
solve this basically is trying to
synthesize more data. That's the most
easy way. we can try to find more data
we can also if we cannot find actually
you can do is a is a data synthesis so
that's why I mention about beside this
kind of the rubrics data this kind of
data efficiency the second thing
actually is the data synthesis
so
data synthesis definitely it work so for
a lot of thing I also continue to use
mass as the example when we do the
publication but actually so mass is just
one one of the work for example we try
to say okay is data things just work to
solve the data quality problem or you
can also trying to solve some other
problem. So this is also another war is
about for example for the math actually
you have the question you have the
answer right so can we synthesize more
questions
so how can we make sure all this
question actually is the right questions
you also have the answer that's
verifiable
that's a verifiable answer so I think
for the math and the answer actually we
try to synthesize a lot of new questions
but we actually we also have a mechanism
to guarantee all these right new
questions test the answer is verifiable.
So this basically mean that actually we
increase the data diversity. we have
more mass it's not like the original
representation anymore actually we have
a way to unlimited I cannot say
unlimited to synthesize a lot of more
datas and another interesting thing is
about for example for the reinforced
learning we know that when we try to do
the reinforced learning there's also
some kind of effect is about the entropy
collapse the entropy is going down
actually when you're trying to improve
the qualities so we found that actually
using the data synite this way it not
only improve the entropy for the pass
one you also input the pass K
significantly as well so
because sometime you use input pass one
but in the IO training most of time
actually the pass K didn't improve but I
think just like I mentioned if you want
the inspiration you need to improve of
the pass K as well so sometimes we
measure we pay a lot of attention to the
pass K mean that actually you just
sample multiple answer so any of them
actually can give you the correct answer
So we found that data synthesis actually
is also very powerful to give us a
better pass at K as well. So you can go
to read the paper and I think that's
also very interesting thing. The other
one because we talk about mass we also
talk about the agent task. So the agent
data actually is super hard to be
synthesized. I cannot share how we
synthesize that but I want to share
maybe for example the Kim K2 actually
also give a really good work is about
how they synthesize the agent datas. So
basically I think the solution is also
pretty simple. So it's just like the
very typical solution. You need the
existing data. They try to get data from
the GitHub. They try to understand okay
this is a tool definition because you
need to synthesize so many different
things. They single side today is pretty
complicated I want to say. So basically
they singleize the tool definition this
kind the task and all these kind of
thing they also have the entire pipeline
to make this kind data synite to be
runnable to be scalable. So for example
they try to synthesize the they take
some existing tool first and they also
try to synize some tour to tour to
definition and the task is also is also
synized
for example is the which one you want to
synize and the agent is also is also
synized and out of that they mix the
synthe data and the original data
together they get from GitHub and to try
to run this to train the model. So
basically you can think about the data
the so one point I want to make here is
the data single size is pretty
complicated today in the industry and we
for me actually I just put the a lot of
best people in the team to work on the
data single size because if I there's a
lot of innovation there so as a PhD PS
student and so I think data synize
actually super important if I want to
open this data I was think about maybe
we think about okay how can we
synthesize the better data because the
training approach will be converge much
easier than the data part. It's so hard
to syncize the data and unfortunately a
lot of industry lab maybe they didn't
share with you how the data was built
but I think this is definitely is the
most exciting part and so for the data
synitizes okay so I think I finished the
most of the part about the data I think
definitely there's a lot of other thing
you can get from about the data yeah but
I think the other thing actually I want
to mention is the lipic is about the
grader so the greater basically
because the greater actually because we
know about is about the experience and
the feedback for example can only be
measured by the greater so if you're
able to define what is greater for the
problem I want to say at at least you
solve half the problem
so
so that is the point for the greater so
for most of our work today every day so
it's figure out what to what to grade
it's not that easy it's not just about
the pass rate it's about for example
even for the coding just by the
representation whether they follow the
behavior whether they is the product
constraint. So every day just think
about okay based on the users
interaction what is what is still
missing. So based on this actually you
understand what to grade and we just add
more and more greater and so
I think add more grader actually is not
an easy task for example some grad is
going to be conflict with some existing
grader you need to understand about how
they their relationship between multiple
graders and so there's second part the
second the third part actually what we
do every day is about how can after you
find figure out okay what do great how
can you prepare the data to be
Right. So you how can you collect data?
So basically greater sometime it's just
part of the data. So it's high it's
highly related and for this time you
want to build a foundation model because
we are also doing this kind of the P
training of the foundation model. So
there's so many things you really care
about
so many different domains just like
medical just like law all these kind of
thing you need to be able to create and
also there are so many different problem
for example even for the coding there
are so many different problem just like
less edic suggestion just like code
completion just like coding agent and so
there's also another thing I want to
mention there's also a lot of product
constraint for example just like
let use the last let's use the coding as
example coding agent because the the
customer like okay can you always
produce some progress to tell me because
this time is pretty long sometimes 10
minutes and I just want to go for a
coffee I don't know okay how many more
minutes you need can you tell me to
share with me the progress so this is
some kind of thing we need to make sure
actually the model is also able to
generate something like this that is the
product constraint it's not just about
the pass rate this kind the single
academic matrix anymore
yeah So, so that's what I say. I think I
already finished this in a previous
talk. Actually, it's about in the
product the greater is so complicated.
It's not just about the pass rate. For
example, there's a lot of Q&A questions.
There's also a lot of multiton
in this kind of the user interaction and
how can you grade the form for format
for example there are some table there's
some mab language. You need to make sure
actually all this is represented in a in
the right way. You also need to solve
the program something like this. You
also need to make sure actually is the
length is not too long. If you're able
to solve the problem in the shorter
length actually definitely nobody will
pre pay preer this kind of the bubbles
and we also try to manage the time to
the poor request and so because it's the
model the model cannot say something
that's very bad as well. So that's all
the thing actually you need a grader to
take care of. So let just use a
holding as an example because basically
this is the thing actually everybody is
using every day. So for example we have
the unit test grader we also have the
patch grader. We also make sure the
format is right I think and all these
kind is trying to grade whether this is
a good coding model based on the
interaction. So if you want to summarize
for example which kind of the grader we
use every day this is the three most
popular one just like I think the first
one is the is very simple is the just
like the unit test we call as the
verifier you able to verify actually
this pass or no pass and the other one
definitely is the we can use another
model to do the grade to use a lot
language model using the prom or
whatever to say okay so to give a score
something like that and the other one
actually is just I mentioned in the data
part is called we based on the rubrics
to do a lot of grading.
So and the other thing actually is just
like I mentioned when you're building
the product you will only put more and
more greater there right. So because you
always want to make sure the model is
able to have a yeah to solve some
problem. So I think a lot of thing yeah
actually when you put more and more
grader it's super hard for the any of
the row to pass all the grader
especially at the beginning the model is
not capable enough you want to say oh
for example just like a kick for three
years old you want to ask okay you need
to follow the rule in the university so
actually the kid don't know about this
so what we did is basically is about we
call as the we didn't try to say about
this pass or not actually we try to do
the ranking to say about okay this is
better than the others. So and based on
the learning for this for this rankings
and the other one definitely is the
quick learning. So for some grader you
can add at the end you don't have at the
beginning because otherwise I don't
think the model can learn anything
because it's too hard at the beginning.
So and you also need to understand the
greater dependency for example this grad
actually have a dependent on that one.
You want to solve this one you need to
solve that one first. So they have this
kind of dependency because some grader
is more strict than the others. So
that's also something we need to think
about and actually you also need to
think about the efficiency. For example,
some grader they need to run in
parallel. So in this case you can make
the entire running much faster
and the as long as you have the grader
you try to graduate something. So the
model is trying to cheat something. It's
going to this kind of hacking cheating
actually based on greater is pretty
normal thingy because the model is so
smart at this moment and we also see a
lot of surprise. For example, when the
model trying to cheat
trying to do the cheat do the cheating
because the model is really smart. For
example, the model can remove all the
test case when you try to ask oh you
need to pass all the test case or the
model can change all the content in the
test case just have the pass there and
so because for example for the coding
task some task actually we also another
example just like a task actually we
need internet access for example just
like we use a sweet bench verify this
kind of the task the model is very
simple they just try try to go for go to
the internet to find the right right
solutions
and then to copy the right solution as
it output. So, so I just want to say the
model is so smart at this and it's so
hard to avoid this kind of cheating. So,
what we did actually is to avoid this
hacking cheating. I think it's the same
thing. So basically we there's also a
lot of thing we did actually we try to
use another model to check the model to
check the model's output to make sure
actually it's not that easy to be cheap
and to use the model to regulate the
model itself we also try we also check
so many different place so you need to
be super careful for example when you
try to change a model based on this and
for example if the model is able to
change the test case we just hide the
test case we just remove all the test
case when you try to run in the in the
sandbox. So and then do the testing and
then after that we patch the test case
back. So for example, we we also try to
say okay if you're able to cheat but I
want to give you a very high penalty if
you cheat again because sometimes it's
so hard to I think I just want to share
there's so many this kind the examples
when you're trying to do the grader for
the trainings you know not that easy you
need to be very very careful it's so
easy for the model to cheat
okay I think that is basically is about
our work about the data including
greater so I think in our time in our
work basically we spend I'm not sure
whether 50% in our daily work is the
exact number but I think we do spend a
lot of time in the data and the grader
when we trying to build a model every
day so and the other part actually what
we spend a lot of time on is the
efficiency because I think when you're
running this kind of the large scale
system how can you make it super
efficient as efficient as possible and
efficiency definitely also include how
can you make things work because if we
know what efficiency is zero so so
that's the part actually I want to
mention how we how we do this today
so how to make the model more efficient
because doing post learning is so
expensive it's just like I say so even
for given one example as long as you be
able to give a lot of compute is able to
learn a lot of things I think it doesn't
mean that actually a lot of computer is
so easy to get and it's so expensive
and this is not only about the GPU
number this also define the iteration
the speed of the iteration as well
so and because I think the model need to
explore a lot so what we did and
definitely I guess you know most of the
industry l so there's a lot of this kind
of asynchronous because reinforced
learning you have the sampler you have
the chainer if they need to wait for
each other they super slow especially in
the large scale so I think you can see a
lot of people actually today it's a lot
of lab actually is using the
asynchronous so as signals because it's
super important how to make the
asynchronous work is also not that easy
especially with with scale and the other
one actually how fast it's just like I
think the one example learning is a is
the instance for understand how
important to enable this kind the policy
exploration how can you enable encourage
the model to explore I think that's also
the most exciting topic research topic
for the I as
There's a lot of optimization what you
need to happen here. How can we enable
it to explore more and so the third one
actually is about how can we control the
sampling cost because the cost is very
high. So we also do a lot of thing to
make the sampling cost much lower. So
actually your entire job can run much
faster. So the last one actually how can
we use Laura to in the RL to make things
work much better or much more efficient.
Okay. Okay, I think asynchronous I just
mentioned I think it's very simple. You
just make it as opposing and actually
the sampler actually because sampler is
the most slow part especially when you
need to sample the chain of saw this
kind the long horizontal. So that's
that's super slow. The sampler actually
is much even slower than the chainer.
Previously we say about okay the trainer
is the most slower but now actually the
sampler is the much more much more slow.
Yeah. So and we definitely in the in our
training we assign much more GPU to the
sampler than for the trainer. So that is
how we work and how things work. So I
think this is just a very simple diagram
about this kind of asynchronous
asynchronous they mean that actually the
trainer and the sampler they need to
they don't need to wait for each other.
You just keep sampling and when you do
the sampling actually you don't need to
be the latest policy. You just keep
sampling and maybe use the policy in the
last iteration.
I think definitely here you need to
there's a lot of work we need to do to
make sure they can converge. It's not
that easy and also this kind the yeah so
we as you can see basically often we
just have one single channel but I think
we have multiple sampler we call as
roller here. You just need to load the
examples. So this roller actually is not
only need to talk to the grader, you
also need to talk to the environment.
For example, to run a unit test or this
kind the this kind the simulator
environment. The greater also need to
talk to environment if you need to do
something.
And so basically they have some way to
sync.
Yeah, I think this is a very simple
diagram, but to make this really work so
well, especially with thousands of GPU,
it's not that easy. There's a lot
there's a tons of work there and because
a lot of thing can happen as long as the
thing is asynchronous.
Yeah. For the quality and the
efficiency. This is the two is so hard
to be to be to be balanced. So the other
thing actually beside a thing I want to
say for the reinforce learning the thing
is about how can we encourage the how
can you encourage the exploration
because the more you are able to explore
actually most likely you are able to get
to a better results.
So in the during the training we want to
encourage this kind of exploration to
make it actually the policy able to
learn more. So
here actually is what we did for the
exploration. I can show you a little
bit. So yeah, we want to get the model
to be able to explore. I think there's a
few thing that's so important. One is
about the model need to understand need
to be able to follow the instruction.
So sometimes for example you say oh this
model is not able to produce a good
result based on the reinforce learning
learning based on the RL a lot of things
is because this model is not able to
follow the instruction
the model is not able to follow the
instruction it's very hard for you to do
a lot of things so in that case you need
to continue to change the model to
follow the instruction force before you
run the
that's also one of the one of the thing
we learned That's also one of the thing
actually for example when you see the
small length model is not able to
produce a good result based on the so I
think the first thing to check is about
how good is this model in following
instruction
so that's one because why want to follow
the instruction so one of the thing for
example we say about the prom how can we
prom the model because you can prom the
model in a different way you can ask the
model oh you can use this method to
solve this math problem you can also use
another method to solve the math
problem. So I think this kind the pmping
approach is very naive right but it's
very very important there are so many
thing you can do in the palm you can
even ask another model to generate the
palm so because if you're able to
generate a have a good prom trying to
prom the model in a different way and
the model is also able to follow the
instruction
so this actually give so many different
diversity for the model to see the
problem in a different way so this mean
that actually the model have so many
different way to run the exploration.
The pumping actually is super important.
It's not that easy. How to build up the
pawn. If you're able to make the pawn
much better, there are so many way you
able to improve the models.
So, so definitely the other thing
actually we also want to control the
length. We don't want the model to
produce unlimited
and so there are so many way for example
you can introduce some noise to do this
kind of inspiration. You can also set up
some different kinds of tools just like
you can try this tool with this for the
first time and try another tool set for
the second times and we can also get rid
of some tools. So to encourage the model
to explore in different kinds of the
environment. So that's also another way
for the exploration.
So and the inspiration the other thing
we face actually because the we know
about reinforce learning there's tool
usage
but the problem is about now today
the user is able to hook up with any of
their own tools when you try to use the
model right you can use the MCP you can
use hook up with your own API and so how
can you make the model to learn for
different tools because the model when
you change the model we don't know about
which tool the user is going to use we
have no ideas yeah because but there's
only one single model you can hook up
with so many different tools I think the
key problem is about how can you do this
kind of tool generalization how can you
generalize the tools so that's also one
of the very important thing and
definitely we also dig a lot of things
but I think the first thing is the
instruction following the model need to
have a very high instruction following
capability if you want the model to
adapt to different tools
And the second one definitely is about
the model can use the tool in the wrong
way during the roll out but you need to
be able to correct itself. The model
need to reflect oh if this cannot solve
the problem can I try different tool and
also this kind the when you change the
model you need to fix the model so many
different kinds of tools and we make
sure the model is able to use the tool
in the prom is also part of the
prompting. If the model didn't use the
tool in the prom you specify it, you
need to give the penalize.
So yeah, you need to try to say the
model actually you are not doing the
good work. So that's also part of the
greater as well.
So the other thing actually as you know
about the efficiency is about the
solution length
because as you know the the bottleneck
is in the sampling but the sampling the
thing is about the model will keep just
doing sampling. the model is so smart.
Okay, if this cannot solve the problem,
I just try again again again and the
model will just keep doing and and here
actually it is more likely to solve the
problem. But I think actually this is
the user experience is no good. For
example, if the same problem and
actually one solution is can be can
finish in one minute, the other one
actually need to finish in one hours.
Definitely you will prefer the one
minute one. So and so this definitely we
need to have a balance between this kind
of the performance and the cost and so
we did definitely we did a lot of thing
to achieve this for example we can ask
the model to solve the problem with
different kind of constraint length
constraint and we always prefer the one
with shorter answers
so that's one yeah so but but the thing
is about this is always a balance if you
know if the cause pity the cost penalty
for the length actually too low. The
model could use unlimited tokens
for the reason motor that you just keep
doing until you get to a he is a better
answer but the cost penalty is too high.
So basically actually you also sacrifice
the exploration for the model because
you don't encourage the model to explore
a longer a longer longer solution. So
this actually is one of the challenge in
our task as well.
So our solution is also pretty simple.
So basically for example here is the one
you didn't control the length. Here is
the one you control the length. So in
the training definitely we want to kept
the very long roll out. If the roll out
is about for some row is 30 minutes or
one hour we say okay no we just give we
just give up. It's a you you need to
have this kind of the mechanisms. So
definitely you need to have the token
cost. This is pretty straightforward. It
depend it highly depends on the lump of
tokens and in the evaluations I think in
the evaluation I think this is more
interesting for example just like when
you guys go to see the sweep sweeping to
verify this kind
most of people just report the pass rate
right they didn't report how long is the
roll out
but I think this has the problem because
actually this highly depends on the
quality in this time the test time
scaling the quality highly depends on
the length
highly depends on how much compute we
want to give in the test time. So in our
internal evaluation we not only care
about the quality we also care about
this kind the raw length. So we want to
with in our opinion actually a lot of
things is not compatible if the raw
length if the test time is not in the
same level. So that is also what we did
here.
So for the there's also a lot of other
thing for example just like the long
context. So even for example there are
some model is able to support up to 1
million tokens but there are some case
there's a lot of case actually
so even 1 million token is not enough so
but today actually for most of the model
is 128k so but 128k is not enough
because the user will just keep doing
and the looutal can be very long and for
example for the coding part some file
actually can be also pretty long as well
so and I think the solution here so I
just use the open source solution to
mention how they solve the problem. So
it's also very basic. This is the paper
from Alibaba. It's called the risk sum.
Basically is about for any of the roll
out or in the history this kind the
early roll out they can try to summarize
it after they summarize there the
summary is always much shorter than the
original text and they just use the
summary to replace the text and so in
this case they can keep keep working. So
I think the idea is is actually is very
simple and this summarizer actually is
also a totally separate separate model
as well.
I think in the real implementation
because you as you know the the detail
is all yeah so there's a lot detail and
there's al so many different kinds of
implementation whether you want to
summarize the entire history or just
want to summarize the row the coot or
you want to keep the original answer
there or you want to keep all the thing
you show to the user there so I think
there's a lot of detail for different
implementations but I think this can
only yeah you can only evaluate this
when you run the experiment by yourself
there are so many different way to do
summization.
>> So the other thing actually we mentioned
a little bit is about is it's about
Lola. Yeah. So and for especially for
the Lola on the reinforce learning. So I
think one of the thing for example I
guess maybe a lot of people know about
know about Lola and there's also a very
very good work from John actually is
Lola without regret. That's also very
important work. So I think they give a
very beautiful wall how to make roller
war without any any regret. So yeah
definitely I would love to promote the
roller wall but I think the other thing
I want to we we also have a lot of
discussion is about why Rola actually
can work in the ring in the
reinforcement learning Chinese because
we know about previously Lola actually
work sometimes
and sometime it didn't work it didn't
know as good as the as the full fine
tuning or something like that but I
think my the answer I try to give is
about I think Lola actually is more
about the regularizations
because basically Lola basically born
with the regularization for example the
main way is keep fix the main way didn't
change so the change actually in term
the way is pretty pretty small no matter
how you did this so and in the
reinforced learning definitely you need
much more regularization than the SFT
for the you don't want the policy to
move away from previous
checkpoint too much. That is one. The
second one especially for the OP policy
chaining
you all you always need a regularization
because if the model if the policy used
for the sampling and the model used to
change the model is very different it's
very hard for the convergence. So you
also this policy learning also need a
lot of regularization.
So definitely that actually is the I
think it married the Lola update very
well. So that's why Lola is so popular
in the reinforce learning. So the other
thing actually definitely there's a lot
of other advantage for Lola as well just
like have less number of the GPU. You
don't need so many GPU and also more
efficient you can train a little bit
faster.
So that's one. The second one I want to
mention is not just about Lola it's
about in the ind lab
for most of the GPU was used we call as
the running a lot of this kind of
experiment just like this kind of data
mix or that kind of data mix we
because everything is a trade-off
we didn't always say about okay we want
to get to the best best setting we
didn't use the optimal setting instead
we we want the most efficient setting
settings even the quality is the one
point less or two point less but we can
run this experiment 2x faster or 3x
faster. So what we did is about we take
this kind the much more efficient
suboptimal setting and put this as the
baseline and put this constraint and
actually we compare all this kind of
change. We make all the change based on
this constraint and then we just do this
kind of the sideby-side comparison. So
this actually will make our innovation
run much faster 2x or 3x faster. I think
that's pretty normal
you you and maybe after you figure out
all this kind of the recipe in the final
run you can run it much longer you can
take all the best setting but I think
previously actually we didn't use all
the best settings. So that's another
thing maybe well guys will feel
surprised why we didn't use all the set
all the optimal settings because it's
too costly.
So yeah, I think that basically is about
capture most of the work I want to
present today. I think actually the
other thing I want to mention is about
because I've been working on
pre-chaining post training and
listening. I'm also working on the
reinforced learning. I try to think
about okay for example if I want to try
to understand this and explain this to
my 11 years old because my daughter
actually 11 years old she love to play
Lego and that's one actually I play Lego
with her and I try to make all all this
kind of the most important concept into
Lego play
so what is pre-chaining
so basically pre-chaining they give you
a lot of datas and this data actually
there's There's no order right you don't
know what is the order here
so we try to figure out when you play
Lego so for the pre-chaining is about
the pre-chaining they want to change the
the scene without order into the scene
with order so what do we mean with order
actually here I try to say about
pre-chaining try to learn the Lego Lego
I call Lego piece the Lego brick the
Lego block they try to learn this time
the Lego block and there are so many of
the Lego block just like and they want
to use this Lego block to simulate the
original data to simulate the war again.
So to build a Lego wall actually this is
the data but I think after you make this
kind of change actually this is the
order.
So because they know okay this wall
representing the data is built by a lot
of different kinds of the structure Lego
broad the Lego bricks so I think that's
how I try to explain this to my 11 years
old what is pre-changing
so
so what is p training and especially for
pre-chaining for example when we compare
a good model or even better model a even
better model basically you're trying to
say about it can build much more
complicated Lego block and you also have
a much more efficient way to assemble
the Lego together to build up this kind
of new Lego world
that is the better pre-chain models
because you always able to learn
something that's much more complicated
the shape is much more complicated so
you just need smaller number of the
piece able to build up this kind the
wall together so the pole training
definitely is also very simple so
basically
you you want what which kind of the Lego
wall you want it to be. So that is the
goal there and that's your task. You
just put this all the piece together to
build up the build up this kind of the
Lego wall for you
with the pre-changing actually the Lego
piece is already there. So that's why
actually pre-changing with the pre-chain
model is able to help you to do this
kind of the post training much
efficiently. So what is reinforced
learning here? Reinforce learning they
basically is a learning concept. It
didn't attach it don't have to be
attached to pre-chaining or prochaining.
There's already a lot of war actually is
also working reinforce learning for the
pre-chaining. So the R basically is just
about it just create
meanings of the this kind the Lego world
or maybe Lego game or whatever and just
get the feedback with the good feedback
say okay I want to build a wall more
like this and without this feedback the
bad feedback okay this is not a good
wall I just want to destroy and you use
this kind of brick take a break build a
new wall again so that is the RL is just
about you're able to figure out this
feedback attack and to build up these
things again and one of the thing
actually I keep thinking about can you
do something new maybe totally different
than the water today I think it's
possible because this inspiration maybe
for example just like if you go to level
water today you see okay most of the
shape actually is that we can find in
the reality maybe in the future maybe
there's always something new actually
you cannot find in the reality that's
about that need to come from as long
Yeah, this kind the very different block
is able to build up something yeah based
on his imagination or creativities for
the model.
Yeah, I think that is about I want to
say okay so look ahead look ahead to me
is also very simple because I only have
two kind of the things one the only
thing common is scaling.
So what we do definitely is the first
one definitely we need to do the testing
times testing time scaling for the
testing time scaling basically there's
only three things so when you try to map
all the activity there's only three
things one is definitely is the deeper
model a very a more even larger model
especially I think for the reasoning the
model need to be deeper a lot of effort
for example just re recurrent work
recently actually just trying to a
different way to make the model deepers.
It's not only about Yeah, I think that
that's super important. Any way to make
the model deeper actually you can have
the reason that's that's my mind. My
point. So the other way it's just like
you grow a new network. You either make
it wider or you either make it deeper,
right? You want to make a model power
more powerful. Definitely there's also a
lot of thing you can do in the
architecture.
So how to make the model wider?
Definitely there's also a lot of other
things you do come the par thinking just
like you can do the par thinking you you
can put multiple way to do the parings
and but I want to say one of the
important thing is about for what we do
today this kind of paring basically is
just about it do it after you change the
model after change the model you just
get the model produce multiple result
and then do the voting or use another
model pick it you didn't think about how
can we consider is during the model
training. I think that's also one of the
interesting topic. It's not just about
the testing time for the for the
training time. I I already know okay for
this model I just want to use it to do
the par thinking it's not just about to
get a single result but how can we do
this? I think there's definitely a lot
of research seen here. The other thing
to do the wider I think is also pretty
simple. You just maybe give it to
multiple agent and so multiple people to
do the same work for you and you see
okay let them co let them coordinate
together. you also have a orchestrator
or a boss or something like that to ask
a lot of people to want the sing for you
and you can assign the t them I think
that's also another way to make it wider
and beside the wider is also the same
the other direction the other dimension
is the longer you want to make the task
the agent is able to run much longer for
example for today just like the coding
you just get the result in a few minutes
but I think maybe in the future actually
you can ask the to do more complicated
task is able to give the result back to
you in one or two days. I think that's
also pretty normal and but I think here
actually there's a lot of thing
definitely is a lot of research topic
here for example how can you solve the
long context how can we try to memorize
the behavior previously it's not that
easy you want to memorize the behavior
from one day ago or something like that
human is very good at this but model is
not that good so there's a lot of thing
we need to do here so
the other thing beside the testing time
scaling
So I want to say the other thing
actually we spend a lot of effort in the
team is about the training time scaling
training time scaling definitely
and the first one is still the data
that's why I mention we put the best
people best tenant in data synize I
think that there's still a lot of thing
to do to do the data synize it's not
yeah we just getting started it's not
the end of the story it's just the
beginning of the story and because for
for today you can see that we are often
limited by the data instead of the
compute
and how can we make the data more
efficient and we have a lot of compute
but I think we are running out of data
there's no much data we able to leverage
to boost the model to another level
so and I also think about the best model
definitely should be built from the best
data for today to define the model
basically I think at least more than
half is based on the data so for all
this kind of interest
So agentic data actually make this data
complexity into another level. I want to
say it's much more complicated and how
can you use multiple agent to synize the
data? How can you synize this kind of
long horizontal data? They are so
complicated. There's still a lot of
thing to do. How can we synize agent
data? That's why I present this kind of
Kim K2 paper. I think they do a very
good work. Yes. So reinforce learning
and reinforce learning definitely. So at
the beginning when I try to think about
the R I think it's also pretty simple to
me beside that example I think reinforce
learning for example if you compare to
the SAP just use the computer to trade
for the robustness for the model for for
today. So in the industry lab basically
it's not only about the is able to make
the result a little bit better is able
to make the result much more robust
because it's not just about the
benchmarking it's also about okay for
example when the user try to use another
way to ask the questions actually you're
able to produce the okay result SAP is
very hard some sometimes that is why we
use the I show popular [snorts] and
actually it use a lot of compute much
much more comput than the SFT but it did
produce the robustness that's super
important for a product
and another thing actually second point
is about for the I truly believe
actually when you change the model you
will make everything right it just keep
going the quality will just keep going
when you figure it with more compute
until here it reach the model model's
limitation
so so that's also very exciting
because we found a way actually we able
to give the compute the model is able to
become better. So there's no even better
way than this. This is one of the big
challenge problem. How can you make the
model better with more compute is no
easy problem for pre-chaining is not
able to do this sometimes and it's also
limited by the data as well.
It's just like another thing I say is
about for the why I put a lot of effort
in the is about it's easy to it's more
about the steerabilities
you able to guide the into the direction
you want this is also very different
than the IHF you train a reward model or
SAP is so hard if for example in the
what you want the model behavior to be
you just define a new grid it's so
flexible so that's why We love IO in
this kind the product settings for
example you just say oh you don't do it
this way you just need to change the
grader to say about you do this way that
is the better reward you do the other
way that is the better reward so it's
it's more about this
yeah so and
it's just like I mentioned we talk about
pre-training we just talk about post
training I'm not sure whether now
actually in academic there's a there's a
war or maybe in the real setting. Okay,
there's a pre-changing team, there's a
post training team and you just
pre-chain the model and then give it
over to the post training model. But
there's a war between them.
I'm not sure whether this war is really
necessary. Even everybody talk about
okay pre- training is for the
compression post training is for the
behavior but I guess maybe but I want to
mention actually RL actually it didn't
just stick with each side. Maybe in the
future there's only two kinds of laws.
One is reinforced learning. The other
one is the next token prediction.
There's al combining together to remove
the wall between prechaining and
postchain. That's also possible. But
let's see. I also don't know. And
there's also last thing actually I want
to mention is about in the future the
best way is the model is able to improve
itself. This kind of the self
improvement actually I think now the
model is very powerful. is become
possible and a lot of this kind of the
frontier lab uh keep working on this
because if you able that's another way
so in the higher level compared to I is
about if you're able to put more compute
and more data to the model is able to
keep improving and in here definitely
the data in the reinforced learning
actually you want to achieve the same
improvement you need to think about how
can you build the data how can you make
the into the game so I think that's the
two piece is most important to me and
definitely the model also need to be
able to do the self refraction able to
understand what is going wrong
previously and to fix it and also the
other one actually I think a lot of
thing if you want to make this it mean
the previous iteration of the model is
not as good as the next iteration of the
model so the weak learner is able to
produce a better learner so I think that
is also one of the we need to figure out
the methodology about this
yeah I think This is actually is maybe
not related to this task. I think it rel
to our daily work. I think it's also
some of the comments is about how can we
change the model because I know so many
people change the model here every day.
I just learned from you guys. Okay, you
work until 5:00 a.m. last night. So I
think training model actually is pretty
hard to be honestly and because you you
need to often to wake up at 3 p.m. 3:00
a.m. figure out okay there's something
wrong to restart the job and then to
discuss the team actually what's it
going wrong here and how can we fix to
immediately quickly relaunch the job to
save the GPU so and you al so I think
one of the thing actually I didn't
mention a lot but super important to us
is the infrastructure because there's a
lot of thing I cannot share in the
infrastructure side but I think that
actually is another biggest pain in the
reality because infrastructure as long
as this come the last scale is not so
stable and you were pretty strugg
struggle for example when something is
not stable your job okay this GPU fail
that GPU know actually lose the
connection there are so many signature
in infrastructure you're very you are
very struggle I think a lot of thing a
lot of time actually was spend in this
kind the instability of the
infrastructure and you feel very yeah
hopeless sometimes why this info how can
I check this model with given this in
given this info and you also because
there's a lot of thing for example
training the model is about 90% of time
actually since things is not working. Uh
for the 10% time things working is
really making a progress. This mean that
is bad. 90% of time you are not making
any progress. You need to be have the
patient.
So that is why training the model is so
hard. But on the other hand training
model is also so fun.
I think maybe that is best one of the
best job in the world.
So yeah, we are so lucky we still yeah
we able to have the opportunity to train
the model and because with so many this
kind of GPU and also you also when you
feel the fulfillment
when your model you train actually is
able to pick the baseline.
Yeah. So I think that this kind the
fulfillment this kind of joy is not that
easy to get from other place because the
baseline actually is the best model in
the world sometimes
and so and because I'm working with the
product team so if your model is able to
use in the product by so many different
peoples and collect the feedback that's
also another kind of the fulfillment as
a researcher or as an engineer.